you know, the best performing asset over
the one-year period, a 5year period, a
10-year period, and you kind of slice it
over any range over the last 10 years,
it's always Bitcoin on top. Insurance is
not something that you can commercially
expect to cover 100% of digital assets.
They're too big for that. You cannot
find an underwriter that can give you a
hundred million insurance program.
There's only one guy that can write an
uncapped insurance policy, and of
course, that's FDIC. and he writes un
uncapped insurance for US dollars
because they can print the dollars that
they have to print. What is your
solution to quantum hacking? So there's
some concern that if you're building a
quantum computer, the first thing you
might do is try to go get Satoshi's
stash. Satoshi, assuming he's not around
to claim his coins anymore. You know,
this means they could get on the move.
And so there's there's two questions for
Bitcoin.
What are the major problems facing
institutional and retail investors when
it comes to custodying your digital
wallets? We're talking about this theme
with our next guest, Mike Belshi, CEO of
BitGo. I'm Dave Lin, host of the Dave
Lin Report. Bonnie from Bonnie
Blockchain. Mike, thanks for coming in.
Thanks for having me. Great to see you
guys. Let's start with the economy. So,
the Fed watch tool is projecting an a
Fed rate cut by around June. That's the
first cut that the markets are pricing
in. What are your expectations for
monetary policy given uh recent tariffs,
trade wars, heightened inflation fears,
unemployment fears, volatility for a
while. Um I think we'll see Bitcoin
trade more or less kind of up and down
and laterally for a while. Uh but later
this year, I think we'll see things
start to grow. Um how the monetary
policy goes, look, there's a lot a lot
up in the air right now. Uh Ukraine, of
course, uh potential war, I guess, now
in Yemen adding more to the mix. Yeah.
Um, and uh, a lot to deal with here with
the tariffs. How do you think markets
are going to respond to an escalation in
the Middle East? The Houthies just got
attacked? I don't think it ever goes
well. Yeah, markets don't like it. Okay.
Well, probably good for defense stocks,
but I want to get your outlook on
Bitcoin then. Um, is Bitcoin a safe
haven asset for this year in light of
volatility?
Bitcoin is always a safe haven asset.
So, look, people talk about is it the Is
it though? I don't I don't mean to
interrupt you, but it goes down when the
stock markets go down. Look, it's been
correlated in the past. It'll get
increasingly uncorrelated over time.
Yeah. Um but if you look at, you know,
the best performing asset over a
one-year period, a 5year period, a
10-year period, and you kind of slice it
over any range over the last 10 years,
it's always Bitcoin on top. So, you
know, people have a hard time with the
volatility, but that volatility uh is is
not to be unexpected given how small
Bitcoin is relative to other markets.
Okay.
You went to the White House crypto
summit. I did. How is it? Uh, look, it's
exciting. It's a it's a an honor and a
privilege to represent BO, represent
some of the industry. Um, a great
collection of leaders were there. Um, it
was good to see a lot of the the early
friends that I've met in the crypto
space all attending this. Um, but it was
it was really a point in time where the
new administration is recognizing that
they are open to working with everybody
that's here at this conference. Um,
whereas the prior administration wasn't.
So, it's not so much a working meeting
as it is kind of a, hey, we're declaring
that there was a problem, we're fixing
it, let's move forward. I think the
number one thing people should take away
from it is we can now have innovation in
digital assets and the new
administration is going to help figure
out how to regulate that, figure out how
to foster innovation in that instead of
being regulation through enforcement,
which was obviously a problem holding
everybody back.
Is there anything the media is not
talking about that has happened at the
summit? Any fun things? Any fun things?
I mean, look, they they uh I wish I
could say they whined and dined us.
People ask me uh what did you eat? We
didn't we didn't have a meal uh there.
They had some cookies and some uh some
coffee, but no, no, they they did roll
out the red carpet in in some terms of
some of the pompom circumstance that you
see behind the scenes. Um, look, it's
obviously experience to to go to the
White House under such conditions, but
uh, what you saw on TV was mo was most
of what there was to see.
Well, David Sax is an investor of Bitco,
um, he's going to be the crypto star.
What's your plan? Well, what's your uh,
feedback or take on his outlook for the
industry and what he may do to change
things up? Look, I've known David for
the better part of 20 years at this
point. Uh, he lives out in the Bay Area.
Uh I would say we're friends. Um
certainly have common viewpoints on a
whole number of things, but David is a
super high intellect guy. Um and you can
see this uh you know in his PayPal
roots, his Yammer sale to Microsoft.
This is a very capable serious serious
guy. Um so he's going to figure things
out. Um I'm I'm really happy to have
that kind of brain power uh in the White
House working on this problem. Have you
heard any plans that he's about to
deploy? He wants to be really
level-headed. I mean, I think you saw
just from his behavior uh in the last
month as he's moved into uh this role,
this is a a very ethical guy that wants
to do things right. So, he wouldn't he
wouldn't give anybody any inside scoop,
I think, even if he could. I see. I see.
Uh by bit hack, it was the biggest hack
in human history. Yeah. Um does that
worry you?
I mean, a little bit for the industry,
right? Like we we have to put an end to
these types of things. um any one of the
failures that occurs whether it's this
one or some of those in the past they
all should be lessons right um and the
positive news on this look I think by
bet responded super well um their uh uh
incident response was was really better
than any we've seen in the past they
were able to cover you know the losses
for all of their clients which of course
makes it a lot easier um but also
there's some mistakes made and I'm sure
that they're thinking about how to deal
with that As we move forward, digital
asset security gets harder and harder.
That's what we do at Vickup, right? So,
we're not an exchange. We're focused on
how do you keep this asset safe and you
know, we've been pioneering this since
the early days. We we have a no
compromises approach to security. Um, we
do two out of three multi-IG, we do two
out of three MPC, we have layers on top
of that, policy controls, etc. Um, so
look, I think increasingly we're going
to need to see separation of duties.
market structure needs to evolve and
we're going to need to see like the
folks that are doing security be hired
to do that security for large amounts of
assets. Well, you offer hot and cold
wallet storage, I believe.
Bitcoin on the security advantages and
disadvantages of both. Well, let's see.
One of the things we believe in is, you
know, decentralization and
centralization. So, when you're talking
about businesses, they're usually using
custody. They should be because they
need business continuity. Um, and uh,
you know, self-custody allows them to
offer some amount straight off their
balance sheet. And you can do a small
amount there. It's the the analogy would
be like what's in your wallet. You
probably have a little bit of cash in
your wallet that you carry with you.
Technically, it's at risk. You could
lose it right now. I could mug you.
Well, I'm not going to mug you. But I
don't know where my wallet is. I took it
already. Okay. That's But you're not too
worried about it. You'd be annoyed, but
you're not too worried about it. But of
course, you still use use custody. So,
uh, everything we do out of custody is
cold storage. We've been pioneering that
for a long time. Um, I think it's what
people expect. Frankly, when you've got
nation state attackers that don't have
to be near you because they're virtual,
right? And they can take the money from
a hot wallet. It's just unacceptable. In
this day and age, you should be using
cold storage for any any sizable amount.
Um, the BBIT attack was using a type of
cold storage. Um, but they also, you
know, made some other mistakes. So, it's
not perfect. Uh, of course these are
addressable problems. Is there any
crypto insurance in place today or how
is it evolving after all these hacks and
institutional adoption?
Look, insurance is an interesting thing.
People say the word insurance, it's a
it's a single word, but it can mean a
lot of things. What does that insurance
cover? Does it cover hacks? Does it
cover insider thefts? Does it cover
natural disasters? These are all
different types of insurance that you
can get. If you ask Bony Melon, they're
probably here somewhere. are you guys
insured for your I don't know how many
trillions of assets? They're going to be
like, no, they're not. They're not
insured. There's only one guy that can
write an uncapped insurance policy. And
of course, that's FDIC. And he writes un
uncapped insurance for US dollars
because they can print the dollars if
they have to print. Um, but other than
that, you can't. So, one challenge with
digital assets is that yes, you should
have insurance. So, Bitco programs that
you can get. It's $250 million plus
there's excess cover up to like 700
million. Um but you know we also have
hundred billion dollars of assets. So
how do you protect a hundred billion
dollars of assets with that side? Look
one of the things we do and this would
have helped the Bybit folks. We already
rebalanced our clients. If you've got
$1.5 billion that's at least 15 wallets
at BCO it would have been chopped up
into hund00 million piles which means
that that particular breach just by
using BO they would have saved $1.4
billion.
That's without even looking at anything,
you know. So that's that's a basic
practice and it would have been in cold
storage. So um look, insurance is not
something that you can commercially
expect to cover 100% of digital assets.
They're too big for that. You cannot
find an underwriter that can give you a
hundred billion insurance program. Just
doesn't exist. But there are things that
you can combine with your security
policies and your insurance to be able
to cover our wallets. Thank you. Well, I
know you service institutional clients
uh primarily I believe, but uh for the
retail audience watching out there, what
advice or lessons have you learned
serving the institutional side that
could be applied for the retail service
side when it comes to security and
insurance of custody? One of the things
I think is a big deal if you're using
someone else's custody is ensuring that
whoever you're put putting that custody
with has a fiduciary duty over your
assets. So, what does that mean? I mean
on one hand it's a bunch of legal mucky
muck but it means that we've gone
through a level of scrutiny with our
regulator. We adhere to a set of
policies. We do things like third party
risk management procedures which sounds
really boring but remember the bybit
hack had a third party that failed. So
understanding like what is your risk and
dependence on third parties is actually
a really key part of what we do. We do
sock audits. We do redundant control so
there's no insider theft cap
possibilities. All right. But when you
have a fiduciary duty, you're known to
your regulators. It's a lot harder to
imagine any type of breach of Pico that
would would steal the money. Um, so this
has been available for institutions.
Institutions demand that they use a
regulated custodian. I think retail
needs to make that same demand. So BO's
recently opened up. Actually, you can
come to BCO. You open up a BCO retail
account, you will get the same
institutional control as a BO that
institutions would get.
I want to congratulate you because Bitco
um recently became the largest
independent crypto custodian. Oh, thank
you. I mean, I think we've been for a
long time, but we just announced a new
milestone. Right. Right. Okay. With OC
now allow traditional banks to enter
crypto custody. Do you see them as
potential partners or enemies? Uh both.
Uh look, we we work with a number of
banks already and provide custody.
Either we do self custody to us and
custody through them uh or they'll use
us as a subcustodian. We can do both of
those models. Um, it's a great way for
them to get started with a lot of
digital assets. We got the best coverage
of any custodian out there. Um, and of
course we would take security to the nth
degree for a long time. Um, at the same
time, look, I think
innovation, smaller companies move
faster than bigger companies. Bitco's
gotten to the point where we've got the
maturity of processes, we've got the
maturity of regulatory controls, those
are all built in place and then we're
still able to move very quickly. So, um,
I think innovation is going to come
faster under the new administration than
not.
And I think we're going to see banking
change in a really positive way for both
institutions and retail. And a lot of
it's going to be thanks to digital
assets. Okay. What is next for the
future of digital security and how does
uh, Big Go fit into this path going
forward? So, security is eliminating
single points of failure. We have seven
trust companies around the globe today.
Okay, we operate two in the United
States here. Switzerland, Germany,
Dubai, Singapore, and coming this year
in South Korea. The purpose of this,
Americans roughly keep their money in
America. Europeans roughly keep it in
Europe. Asians roughly keep it in Asia.
This is the way it's always been. It's
difficult to open foreign accounts. You
might have done some of it. Uh it's it's
it's complex. Regulators are also going
to demand that the assets roughly stay
in region. The reason we've connected
all these trust companies is because now
you can be operating on Singapore. You
interface with Singaporean banks, a
Singaporean regulated BICO, you can be
in the United States, you're talking to
US banks, you're talking to US regulated
Bitcoin single points of failure by way
of a couple of things here. A, you get
to keep regionally. you don't have to
put all in one big honeypot, but B, when
you start to talk about multi-
signature, we can start to take these
keys and put them all over the place. So
instead of having keys all at a BCO, all
out of Coinbase, etc., we can put keys
in multiple institutions. What is your
solution to quantum hacking, the advent
of quantum computers, that's not a
custody problem. That's a oh shoot,
everything's at risk problem. Look, good
news is we have a little time. Okay, bad
news, technology moves really fast and
uh you know, Bitcoin development in
particular uh is known for being slow by
design, which is good, right? If you
want to invest in something to a billion
dollars, you want to know it's not going
to change right underneath you. Um look,
I know a lot of the folks on the Bitcoin
side are working on this problem.
There's some quantum resistance already
built in. When you use multi-ig,
actually, you're better off than if
you're not. If you're using single key
wallets or MPC wallets, those are more
vulnerable. Um but anyway there's
efforts among those of those of us that
have been in the industry for a long I
don't mean to bring up bipid one more
time but they have multisync as well
right it's not impenetrable
uh correct there's different types of
breaches on different types of attack
surface areas when you talk about
quantum computing quantum computing
would be trying to brute force your
private key and that's much easier on a
single sig wallet than on a multi-IG
wallet um multisig uh definitely
protects against any single point of
failure remember by had a single point
of failure in that they were all using
the safe wallet UI. Would AI overwrite
the uh human aspect of multisync? They
could impersonate people identities.
Would AI look I mean I can't deny that
there's probably some uh some breach
that you can imagine. Um but no uh not
by itself like you know what's the point
of security? You you eliminate single
points of failure. If you have a key
held by one person, you split it across
two. If it's held at one company, you
split it across two. If it's held in one
jurisdiction, you split it across two.
And then if two is not good enough, you
go to three and four and five. Um, so
when you do that, even for AI, it's
going to have to figure out how to
penetrate each of those independent, you
know, keys. So no, AI is is not not a
magic penetration. Sure. on um quantum
computing. So, I asked a lot of experts
about this and they said we're way too
far to talk about that or people would
say um if that happens, Bitcoin would be
the last thing you worry about. So, I
want to get your opinion on this. Look,
one of the things is Satoshi's coins
which haven't moved for a long time.
they are on the chain in a way that you
can see the public key which means they
are more reachable by quantum computing
than the current format. So there's new
formats like when you're using your keys
you don't expose your your public keys
generally. Um so there's some concern
that if you're building a quantum
computer the first thing you might do is
try to go get Satoshi's stash. Um and
it's a reasonable
concern. Satoshi, assuming he's not
around to claim his coins anymore, you
know, this means they could get on the
move. And so there's there's two
questions for Bitcoin. Number one is how
do you make it quantum computing
resistant? And that may need some time.
The second one is even if we do make all
the new wallets quantum resistant, what
happens to Satoshi's old coins? Um, so
look, I think that is a potential
attack. There's discussion about would
you free Satoshi's coins? Now, that goes
against the ethos of everything that's
Bitcoin, right? Like, you're not
supposed to freeze coins. Um, but look,
humans at the end of the day all
together collectively govern Bitcoin and
we'll do we'll figure out a solution to
that particular problem. Again, I think
we have enough time to solve it. But I
also think we should not dillydally. We
should get on it now and then maybe in 3
years time we'll have a solution.
Quantum computing won't be here yet, but
we'll all feel safe. By the way, with
security, one last thing, you're never
done, right? So, the level of security
that you would employ back in 2011 to
secure the entire Bitcoin blockchain was
very low. It wasn't worth that much,
right? And then by the time it's 2013
and 2015, you start to see
million-dollar wallets and then hundred
million dollar wallets and then today
billion dollar wallets. And the level of
security that you employ, you have to
keep going up. So, the same thing is
true as Bitcoin grows. uh it's incumbent
upon the Bitcoin ecosystem to figure out
how to make sure it is applying the
appropriate level of security for the
size of asset that it is. Dubonni has
earlier question about banks now being
able potentially custody uh cryptos. How
would you evaluate the security of
traditional financial systems compared
to you know a custody solution like
yourself right now? Look, we are
refiguring out how to deal with bearer
instruments. um you've probably seen in
the movies bearer bonds, right? And you
you may not be familiar, but bear bonds
for the most part have been removed from
our financial system. Um and that came
back from uh laws back in the late 1980s
where the US disallowed bearer bonds
because we didn't know how to secure
things that were bearer instruments. We
now have to figure that out again. And
um good news, it's digital. We have
digital capabilities. And so I I believe
we are solving those problems. Um, it is
doable today, but people need to take
great care.
I think that about sums it up. Uh, Mike,
great coming. Great to have you come in
and u and, uh, we'll speak again soon.
All right. Thanks for having me. Thanks.